Guide to the Women Hospital Workers Oral History Collection OH.006
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Women Hospital Workers Oral History Collection
1979
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Sexton, Patricia Cayo
OH.006
2 Linear Feet in 1 letter manuscript box, 1 half letter manuscript box, and 2 flat boxes.
67 audiocassettes
The Women Hospital Workers Oral History Collection (1979) contains interviews of hospital workers conducted in 1979, including both recorded interviews on audiocassettes and interview transcripts. The interviewees are primarily women, with a few men represented as well. They are members of SEIU Locals across the United States, and include nurses, nursing attendants, lab supervisors, researchers, therapists, food service workers, custodians, business agents, secretaries, and more. They discuss topics such as experiences of sexism and racism on the job, working conditions, union organizing, the women's movement, maternity leave, pay inequities, and workplace hierarchies. The collection includes both recorded interviews on audiocassettes and interview transcripts.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Patricia Cayo Sexton in circa 1979. The accession number associated with this collection is 1950.129.
Arrangement
Interviews are arranged alphabetically by the interviewee's last name. Some interviews include multiple participants, and are based on a particular topic such as the women's movement; in these cases, they are arranged alphabetically by the subject of the interview. Some recordings are compilations that include parts of multiple interviews; in these cases, both interviewee names are listed in the title field and the recordings may not be grouped together alphabetically with other parts of the same interview.
Historical Note
Healthcare workers first joined Service Employees International Union (SEIU) in 1941, when workers in San Francisco organized their hospital and won their first contract. Interview participants represented in this collection come from SEIU Locals across the United States.
Many of the interviews reference George Hardy's leadership as President from 1971-1980. During his tenure, the union saw rapid growth and organized its first local union of physicians. Merges and affiliations accounted for much of the growth during this time. There is also much discussion of the 1966 hospital workers strike in Los Angeles, which led to the Meyers-Milias-Brown Act, the first public employee law on collective bargaining in California.
In addition to union organizing, history and structure, the interview participants discuss at length their thoughts on the women's rights movement and experiences of sexism and racism at work. Major themes include paid maternity leave, discrimination faced by pregnant women, pay inequity, and workplace sexual harrassment. The participants also discuss their relationship with the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW), a national organization that formed in 1974 to advocate for women's issues within the labor movement.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Scope and Contents
The Women Hospital Workers Oral History Collection contains interviews of hospital workers conducted in 1979, including both recorded interviews on audiocassettes and interview transcripts. The interviewees are primarily women, with a few men represented as well. The creator of this collection and conductor of the interviews are unknown. In some interviews with women participants, the first name of the interviewee is omitted from source materials and therefore unknown.
The interviewees are members of SEIU Locals across the United States, and include nurses, nursing attendants, lab supervisors, researchers, therapists, food service workers, custodians, business agents, secretaries, and more. They discuss topics such as experiences of sexism and racism on the job, working conditions, union organizing, the women's movement, maternity leave, pay inequities, and workplace hierarchies. Some interviews include multiple interviewees, and are based on a particular topic such as the women's movement. Not all audio recordings have a transcript, and not all transcripts have an audio counterpart.
Hospitals -- United States -- History.; Strikes and lockouts -- United States.; Hospitals -- Employees -- Labor unions; Hospitals -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.; Hospitals -- Employees -- Interviews.; Labor unions; Labor unions -- Organizing.; Women's rights -- United States -- 20th century; Women employees.; Women employees -- New York (State) -- New York -- Interviews.; Women in the labor movement -- United States; Women -- Employment -- United States.; Sexton, Patricia Cayo; Service Employees International Union; Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.)
- Allison, Sylvia -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Arballo, Bill / McFadden, Ophelia, September 4, 1979; cuid43888 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_001)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Duration: 90 min
  Scope and Contents
  This recording includes the first part of Ophelia McFadden's interview.
  Related Materials
  For the transcript of Bill Arballo's interview, see Box 1, Folder 2.
  For the transcript of Ophelia McFadden's interview, see Box 1, Folder 55.
- Arballo, Bill -- Transcript, September 4, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  For the audio recording of this interview, see audiocassette 006_001.
- Ball, Dolores / Faniel, Diana, September 10, 1979; cuid43889 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_002)
  Duration: 95 min
  This recording includes the first part of Diana Faniel's interview.
  For the transcript of Dolores Ball's interview, see Box 1, Folder 3.
  For the transcript of Diana Faniel's interview, see Box 1, Folder 26.
  For the second part of Diana Faniel's interview, see audiocassette 006_021.
- Ball, Dolores -- Transcript, September 10, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  For the audio recording of this interview, see audiocassette 006_002.
- Beasley, Cora, August 23, 1979; cuid43824
  - Audio recording, cuid43890 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_003)
    Duration: 40 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 of the tape is blank
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bierer, Charlene -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bisher, Sondra, June 22, 1979; cuid43825
  - Audio recording, cuid43891 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_004)
    Duration: 96 min
  - Audio recording, cuid43892 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_005)
    Duration: 43 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 of the tape is blank
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bragg, Lily, August 20, 1979; cuid43826
  - Audio recording, cuid43893 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_006)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brooks, Dovie, August 20, 1979; cuid43827
  - Audio recording, cuid43894 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_007)
    Duration: 57 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brooks, Mae, September 6, 1979; cuid43828
  - Audio recording, cuid43895 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_008)
    Duration: 34 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 of the tape is blank
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Broussard, Bobbie, August 23, 1979; cuid43829
  - Audio recording, cuid43896 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_009)
    Duration: 45 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 of the tape is blank
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Brumfield, Anna / Garcia, Susana, June 15, 1979; cuid43897 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_010)
  This recording also includes 10 minutes of Susanna Garcia's interview.
  Duration: 32 min
  For the other part of Anna Brumfield's interview, see audiocassette 006_011.
  For the transcript of Anna Brumfield's interview, see Box 1, Folder 11.
  For the other parts of Susana Garcia's interview, see audiocassettes 006_025 and 006_026.
  For the transcript of Susana Garcia's interview, see Box 1, Folder 31.
- Brumfield, Anna, June 15, 1979; cuid43898 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_011)
  For the other part of Anna Brumfield's interview, see audiocassette 006_010.
- Brumfield, Anna -- Transcript, June 15, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  For the audio recordings of this interview, see audiocassettes 006_010 and 006_011.
- Bryant, Ollie -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Butterfield, Sandy -- Transcript, September 18, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  For the audio recording of this interview, see audiocassette 006_012.
- Cabell, Connie -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Caton, Vivian -- Transcript, September 12, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  For the audio recording of this interview, see 006_013.
- Caton, Vivian / Daniels, Ophelia, August 28 - September 12, 1979; cuid43900 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_013)
  Duration: 46 min
  For the transcript of Vivian Caton's interview, see Box 1, Folder 15.
  For the transcript of Ophelia Daniels' interview, see Box 1, Folder 17.
- Collins, Mary Ann -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Daniels, Ophelia -- Transcript, August 28, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Dixon, Mae / Troy, Susan, September 5, 1979; cuid43902 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_014)
  This recording includes the first part of Susan Troy's interview.
  Duration: 88 min
  For the transcript of Mae Dixon's interview, see Box 1, Folder 18.
  For the transcript of Susan Troy's interview, see Box 4, Folder 5.
  For the second part of Susan Troy's interview, see audiocassette 006_060.
- Dixon, Mae -- Transcript, September 5, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  For the audio recording of this interivew, see audiocassette 006_014.
- Douglas, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Biographical Note
  The participant's name is listed as "Mrs. Douglas" with her first name omitted.
- Dowden, Hellan, September 17, 1979; cuid43835
  - Audio recording, cuid43903 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_015)
    Duration: 92 min
  - Audio recording, cuid43904 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_016)
    Duration: 28 min; Preservation Notes: Side 2 of the tape is blank
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Drozd, Paul, circa 1979; cuid43836
  - Audio recording, cuid43905 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_017)
    Duration: 76 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Dumbauld, Deborah, July 17, 1979; cuid43837
  - Audio recording, cuid43906 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_018)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Edwards, Audrey, August 17, 1979; cuid43838
  - Audio recording, cuid43907 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_019)
    Duration: 77 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Edwards, Patsy, August 22, 1979; cuid43839
  - Audio recording, cuid43908 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_020)
    Duration: 55 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Estrada, David -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Faniel, Diana, September 10, 1979; cuid43840
  - Audio recording, cuid43910 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_021)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Filapowski, June -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Floyd, Robin / Richardson, Ann, September 10, 1979; cuid43911 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_022)
  This recording includes part of Ann Richardson's interview.
  Duration: 87 min
  For the transcript of Robin Floyd's interview, see Box 1, Folder 28.
  For the transcript of Ann Richardson's interview, see Box 1, Folder 69.
  For the other part of Ann Richardson's interview, see audiocassette 006_049.
- Floyd, Robin -- Transcript, September 10, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  For the audio recording of this interview, see audiocassette 006_022.
- Gallelos, Esperanza, September 5, 1979; cuid43842
  - Audio recording, cuid43912 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_023)
    Duration: 53 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Gantt, September 7, 1979; cuid43843
  The participant's name is listed as "Mrs. Gantt" with her first name omitted.
  - Audio recording, cuid43913 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_024)
    Duration: 59 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Garcia, Susana, September 13, 1979; cuid43844
  For the other parts of Susana Garcia's interview, see audiocassettes 006_010 and 006_026.
  - Audio recording, cuid43915 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_025)
    Duration: 64 min; Preservation Notes: Side 1 of the tape includes recorded over content that is still audible; Side 2 of the tape contains the same issue as Side 1, but it is less pronounced.
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Geagan, John -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Glenn, Elinor -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Group Interview: Marilyn Mbagwn and Carolyn Riley, September 12, 1979; cuid43887 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_051)
- Grystar, Ed, June 14, 1979; cuid43845
  - Audio recording, cuid43917 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_027)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Haer, John, June 13, 1979; cuid43846
  - Audio recording, cuid43918 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_028)
    Duration: 66 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Hangford, Susie / Butterfield, Sandy, August 28, 1979; cuid43847 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_012)
  Duration: 86 min
  For the transcript of Sandy Butterfield's interview, see Box 1, Folder 13.
- Hardy, George -- Transcript, November 28, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  For the audio recording of this interview, see audiocassette 006_029.
- Hardy, George / Polisar, Lisa, November 28, 1979; cuid43870 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_029)
  Duration: 50 min; Preservation Note: Tape contains poor audio quality
  For the transcript of George Hardy's interview, see Box 1, Folder 36.
- Hawkins, Rita -- Transcript, September 6, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  For the audio recording of this interview, see audiocassette 006_030.
- Hawkins, Rita / McCone, Helen, September 6-13, 1979; cuid43920 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_030)
  Duration: 79 min
  For the transcript of Rita Hawkins' interview, see Box 1, Folder 37.
  For the transcript of Helen McCone's interview, see Box 1, Folder 54.
- Herschberger, Cheryl, June 25, 1979; cuid43850
  - Audio recording, cuid43921 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_031)
    Duration: 65 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Jackson, Lois -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Kassalow, Sylvia -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Keener, Stephanie -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Keffer, Kathy, June 29, 1979; cuid43851
  - Audio recording, cuid43922 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_032)
    Duration: 68 min; Preservation Note: Tape has a muted sound quality that is considerably worse on side 2.
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Kimmel, Phyllis -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Krauss, Al, September 19, 1979; cuid43852
  - Audio recording, cuid43923 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_033)
    Duration: 80 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 of the tape contains a loud tapping in rapid succession that is heard every few seconds.
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Kravice, Cecilia, July 6, 1979; cuid43853
  - Audio recording, cuid43924 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_034)
    Duration: 56 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Kronk, Jane, July 10, 1979; cuid43854 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_035)
  Duration: 55 min; Preservation Note: The volume on side 1 fluctuates.
- Kujawa, Elsie, June 26, 1979; cuid43855
  - Audio recording, cuid43925 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_036)
    Duration: 60 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Langford, Susan -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Long, Diane, August 27, 1979; cuid43856
  - Audio recording, cuid43926 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_067)
    Duration: 82 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Lopez, Josephine / Garcia, Susana, August 20, 1979; cuid43857 (Box 2, Audiocassette 006_026)
  This tape also includes part of Susana Garcia's interview.
  For the transcript to Susana Garcia's interview, see Box 1, Folder 31.
  For the other parts of Susana Garcia's interview, see audiocassettes 006_010 and 006_025.
- Love, Evelyn -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Luna, Eileen, September 6, 1979; cuid43858
  - Audio recording, cuid43927 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_037)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Luna, Maria, August 27, 1979; cuid43859
  - Audio recording, cuid43928 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_038)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Maricondia, Pat -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Marigny, Gloria, August 23, 1979; cuid43860
  - Audio recording, cuid43929 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_039)
    Duration: 64 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 53)
- McCone, Helen -- Transcript, September 13, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- McFadden, Ophelia -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Miller, Walter, August 14, 1979; cuid43862
  - Audio recording, cuid43931 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_040)
    Duration: 63 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Mills, Nancy / Remson, Ann, May 14, 1979; cuid43932 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_041)
  Duration: 69 min
  For the transcript of Nancy Mills' interview, see Box 1, Folder 57.
  For the transcript of Ann Remson's interview, see Box 1, Folder 66.
  For the other part of Ann Remson's interview, see audiocassette 006_048.
- Mills, Nancy -- Transcript, May 14, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  For the audio recording of this interview, see audiocassette 006_041.
- Murphy, Dick, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Mushenski, Nancy, September 11, 1979; cuid43864
  - Audio recording, cuid43933 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_042)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Nicklow, Rosella, June 29, 1979; cuid43865
  - Audio recording, cuid43934 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_043)
    Duration: 83 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 60)
- O'Connor, Fotine, circa 1979; cuid43866
  - Audio recording, cuid43935 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_044)
    Duration: 46 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 of the tape is blank
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Oravetz, Pauline, June 28, 1979; cuid43867
  - Audio recording, cuid43936 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_045)
    Duration: 80 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Organizing Women Hospital Workers, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Pearman, Sally, June 22, 1979; cuid43868
  - Audio recording, cuid43937 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_046)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Piper, Carolyn, June 26, 1979; cuid43869
  - Audio recording, cuid43938 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_047)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Remson, Ann -- Transcript, September 12, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Reynouard -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  The participant's name is listed as "Mr. Reynouard" with his first name omitted.
- Rice, Marjorie -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Richardson, Ann, September 19, 1979; cuid43872
  For the other part of this interview, see audiocassette 006_022.
  - Audio recording, cuid43942 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_049)
    Duration: 9 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 of the tape is blank
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Ridgely, Hattie, June 27, 1979; cuid43873
  - Audio recording, cuid43943 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_050)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Riley, Carolyn -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Rodriguez, Margarita -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Saland, Bonnie / Remson, Ann, August 22 - September 12, 1979; cuid43874 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_048)
  For the transcript of Ann Remson's interview, Box 1, Folder 66.
  For the other part of Ann Remson's interview, see audiocassette 006_041.
- Santore, Rosemary, June 21, 1979; cuid43875
  - Audio recording, cuid43944 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_052)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Singleton, September 7, 1979; cuid43876
  - Audio recording, cuid43945 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_053)
    Duration: 49 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Smith, Rosina, September 13, 1979; cuid43877
  - Audio recording, cuid43946 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_054)
    Duration: 36 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 of the tape is blank
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Smouse, Claudia -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Staszel, Emma, June 21, 1979; cuid43878
  - Audio recording, cuid43947 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_055)
    Duration: 72 min
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Stirbis, Flo, July 11, 1979; cuid43879
  - Audio recording, cuid43948 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_056)
    Duration: 85 min
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Stoffel, Leonore -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Taylor, circa 1979; cuid43880
  The participant's name is listed as "Ms. Taylor" with her first name omitted.
  - Audio recording, cuid43949 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_057)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Thompson, Evelyn, circa 1979; cuid43881 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_058)
  Duration: 88 min; Preservation Note: This recording has very low volume.
- Tissue, Dolores, June 27, 1979; cuid43882
  - Audio recording, cuid43950 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_059)
    Duration: 70 min
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Troy, Susan, September 13, 1979; cuid43883
  For the first part of this interivew, see audiocassette 006_014.
  - Audio recording, cuid43952 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_060)
    Duration: 31 min
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Trujillo, Alice, September 10, 1979; cuid43884
  - Audio recording, cuid43953 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_063)
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Trump, Rose, July 7, 1979; cuid43885
  - Audio recording, cuid43954 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_061)
  - Audio recording, cuid43955 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_062)
    Duration: 31 min; Preservation Notes: Side 2 of the tape is blank
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Union Structure and History, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  This interview features Elinor Glenn, John Geagan, June Filapowsky, Dick Murphy, and Stephanie Keener.
- Weinlein, Anthony -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Welsh, Bob -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Welsh, Geagen -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Werry, Rita -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Wiltrout, Virginia, June 21, 1979; cuid43886
  - Audio recording, cuid43956 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_064)
  - Audio recording, cuid43957 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_065)
  - Audio recording, cuid43958 (Box 3, Audiocassette 006_066)
    Duration: 8 min; Preservation Note: Side 2 of the tape is blank.
  - Transcript (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Wisniewski, Judith -- Transcript, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Women Hospital Workers Questionaire, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Women's Issues, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Women's Movement, CLUW, circa 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)